

Daniele Gazzelloni

Frontend and Web Application developer

SANTA CRUZ DE TENERIFE, 38650, SPAIN

Frontend and web application developer with strong expertise on React and JavaScript-based technologies, like Meteor.js.

I graduated in Computer Engineering in 2012 and *I work remotely* with startup and companies located in EU and US since then.

I'm a proud follower of lean and agile software development methods. I try to avoid messaging or communicating too much when not needed, moving through sprints and user stories and iterate in prototyping to give and have regular feedbacks. Able to manage myself without the need of a boss, take independent decisions and suggest development strategies.

My work style is focused and detail oriented. I always strive to write the most clean and elegant code.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Engineering, University of Rome "La Sapienza", Rome

November 2012

"Integration of an anti-plagiarism software into an e-learning system"

Thesis focused on web programming skills, including:

- Development of Learning Management System plugin, Moodle 1.9.3
- Software integration with an anti-plagiarism tool called "similarity-tester" (by Dick Grune) into my PHP code
- Software integration with Graphviz, an vectorial graphic drawing library, to draw runtime graphs and nodes

Employment History

Meteor.js and3 frontend development at 33 Mile Radius, remote December 2015 – August 2018

Developer and maintainer of "Aquirly", a review generation tool I built from scratch for 33 Mile Radius. Acquirly is an hybrid app built on top of Meteor, a full-stack JavaScript platform based on Node.js.

The app can be currently reached out at https://acquirly.33mileradius.com/ or downloaded for free from Google Play and Apple Store (account required).

Parallel to this I've done mostly frontend work for the company, like enhancing websites, layout remodelling and building UI elements.

Main responsibilities:

- · Full-stack web and mobile development
- Frontend development
- · Wordpress development and content management
- Writing documentation

Details

Av. Rafael Puig Lluvina 34, S.Cruz de Tenerife, 38650, Spain +34 685 931 048

daniele@danielegazzelloni.com http://www.danielegazzelloni.com/

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

1988-04-17 Aprilia, LT

NATIONALITY

Italian

Social Profiles

Github

LinkedIn

Languages

English

Spanish

Italian

Skills

React / Redux

JavaScript (ES6)

Meteor.js

CSS3 / HTML5

jQuery / AJAX

Sass (SCSS)

Twitter Bootstrap

Node.js

PHP

Wordpress development

RESTful APIs

Website development for Chantal Biondi, remote

December 2017 - January 2018

http://www.chantalbiondi.com/ - full WordPress theme development, from design idea to product delivery.

Full-stack development at Credijusto, remote

October 2015 – November 2015

Dashboard components for Credijusto, a Mexican bank.

Skills used involved Twitter Bootstrap and React.js for front-end, writing RESTful APIs, web hooks and API protection mechanisms for backend (stack: Node.js/Express/PosgreSQL). Documentation writing included.

Backend developer at NewNeed Srl., remote

June 2015 – August 2015

Development of backend components (Node.js, REST APIs) and client-side components of a WebGL model editor written in Three.js (https://threejs.org/), a Javascript 3D library.

Full-stack and web development at Elance-oDesk, remote

April 2015 – November 2015

Full stack and web development on Elance-oDesk, now formerly Upwork. Various little projects for clients here and there, mainly using Node.js and the MEAN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.js and Node.js).

My Upwork profile: https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~01cd82d9743d60f9d1 (account needed)

Backend developer at Technology Trading Consulting, remote

September 2014 – February 2015

"Hermes", an enterprise portal - import-export industry

Main developer of an import-export enterprise managerial portal. The software was mainly built in Node.js and Ext.js, respectively for the back-end and front-end. RabbitMQ, RESTful API, modularity, redundancy and security was the keywords.

This enterprise application was conceived as modular and connected with a front-end web interface built in Ext.js.

Each Hermes module communicated with each other through an AMPQ queue messaging system and through HTTP/FTP requests. I also developed a strong authentication management server in a different, remote and dedicated machine.

Main responsibilities:

- · Back-end development
- · Testing and debugging
- · Database management
- · Writing documentation

Webpack

MongoDB, NoSQL

MySQL, SQL

Git

Docker

Shell scripting

Hobbies

Rock climbing, running and generally staying in contact with nature

Game development at Technology Trading Consulting, remote

February 2014 - July 2014

"Il Richiamo dell'Avventura", a 3D Windows game written for educational and rehabilitation purposes. Developed using the popular game engine Unity 3D Pro (4.3.3). Mainly coding using TypeScript and C#.

Main responsibilities:

- · Environment creator and designer
- · Coding of animations (scripts) and in-game mechanics
- · Testing and debugging
- · Writing documentation

Junior Software Developer at Wizard Consulting Group, Pomezia, Italy

July 2013 - October 2013

Development and testing of Windows desktop software using C# and .NET framework. I also used to be the team CSS specialist, prototyping new ideas from paper to code.

Courses

Java / J2EE full course, Wizards Consulting Group, Pomezia, Italy May 2013 – June 2013

OPEN SOURCE PUBLICATIONS

SIM-Plagiarism

November 2012

A PHP plugin developed for Moodle v1.9, a Learning Management System commonly used in universities and public institutes.

It was conceived and developed as a project for my bachelor thesis. The plugin has been published in the Moodle plugin directory at the following URL (not maintained anymore):

https://moodle.org/plugins/view.php?plugin=assignment_uploadcode

"SIM-Plagiarism is a plagiarism detection plugin for Moodle 1.9.* that uses the similarity-tester and Graphviz packages."